Guide to the Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Individuals A-L, Series I
  - Little, Charles
    1818 - Born in Columbia, CT; 1844 - B.A. Yale; 1844-1846 - Auburn Theological Seminary; 1847 - Ordained; married Amelia M. Newton (died 1848); sailed for India where he was a missionary in Madura, South India under the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions; 1853 - Married Susan Robbins; 1858 - M.A., Yale 1859-1888 - Served as pastor in New York, Connecticut, Iowa, and Nebraska;1892 - Died
    - Correspondence: primarily letters from Little in India to his brother, Saxton B. Little, ca. 1850 (Box 103)
    - Writings: handwritten material regarding education and journal written in 1856 regarding a journey in India, 1856, n.d. (Box 103)
  - Lockwood, Peter
    1798 - Born, son of John Davenport Lockwood; - Minister in upstate New York, Binghamton area; 1882 - Died
    - Thirty-six manuscript sermons, 1820-1859, n.d. (Box 197)
    - Journal written in Richmond, 1821-1822 (Box 197)
  - Lord, Benjamin
    1694 - Born in Saybrook, CT; 1714 - Graduated from Yale College; 1717-1783 - Ordained, served church in Norwich, CT;1784 - Died
    - One ms. sermon, 1772 (Box 214)
  - Love, Olive D.
    Love was a missionary serving under the Africa Inland Mission in Blukwa, Djugu, Belgian Congo.
    - Publicity cards for Olive D. Love and the Brashler family; documents certifying the receipt of "la Médaille d'Or de l'Ordre du Lion" given to Olive Love by the Belgian Congo government, 1951-1952, n.d. (Box 387, Folder 14)
    - 108 unidentified snapshots showing Congo children and adults in groups and in scenes of daily life and religious practice; a few include Ms. Love or other missionaries, ca. 1950s (Box 387, Folder 15)
    - 39 negatives "taken by missionary of Bukwa, Africa" incl. scene of native wedding, dance, school girls, missionaries, ca. 1920s (Box 387, Folder 16)
  - Lutzweiler, James
    Lutzweiler was Archivist at Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary.
    - Memoir regarding Lutzweiler's aunt, Elsie Rohrer, who served as a missionary in India in an orphanage founded by Pandita Rambai., 2009 (Box 282, Folder 14)
- Individuals M-Z, Series II
  - McCune, Evelyn Becker
    Evelyn Becker McCune (1907-2012) was born in Pyongyang, Korea, daughter of Methodist missionaries Arthur and Louise Becker.
    - DVD documents McCune's life, 2012 (Box 303, Folder 12)
  - McFarland, George Bradley and Bertha
    The McFarlands were Presbyterian missionaries in Thailand ca. 1920s-1940s; George McFarland was born in Thailand, son of Presbyterian missionaries and taught at Chulalankarana University, Bangkok.
    - Circular letter from Bertha McFarland; holograph letter to "John" from Bertha McFarland; announcement describing the Thai-English dictionary compiled by George McFarland, 1941 (Box 334, Folder 1)
  - McLean, Allen
    1781 Jun 20 -Born in North Bolton (now Vernon), CT; 1805 - Graduated from Yale and afterward studied with Dr.Timothy Dwight in New Haven and the Rev. Asahel Hooker in Goshen; 1809-1861 -Minister of the Congregational Church, Simsbury, Connecticut; 1861 Mar 19 -Died.
    - Printed transcript of Allen McLean's memoir "My Farewell to the World and All it Contains", copied from manuscript by the Rev. George McLean Milne (YDS Class of 1940). (101 pp.) Appendices include genealogy of the McLeans of Simsbury, CT and three facsimile pages of the original text., ca. 1860 (Box 270)
  - McQuary, Rodney L.
    1888 - Born in Atlanta, MO; 1913 - B.A., Cotner College, Nebraska; 1913 - Ordained in Bethany, Nebraska (Disciples of Christ);1916 - B.D., Yale Divinity School; 1916, 1922 - Graduate work at University of Chicago; received D.D. from Univ. of Chicago; 1916-1917 - Professor of Sacred Literature, Eureka College; 1917-1919 - Chaplain of 333rd Heavy Field Artillery regiment, a.k.a. "Blackhawk Regiment"; 1919-1922 - Pastor of 1st Christian Church, South Bend, IN; 1922- Taught Church History at Transylvania University in Lexington, KY for several years; 192? - Pastor of 1st Christian Church in Anderson, IN for four years; responsible for establishment of the Wayside Mission in downtown area of city; 1930 - Moved to Minnesota; pastor of Lynnhurst Congregational Church in Minneapolis for seventeen years; 1933, summer - Exchange minister in England and Scotland; 1948 - Accepted appointment from Los Angeles Presbytery to found a Presbyterian Church in Malibu, CA.; the Malibu Community Presbyterian Church was formally organized in November, 1948; 1965 - Retired; spent retirement years in Friday Harbor, WA; wrote many of the typescript manuscripts included in this collection;1977 - Died.
    - The Apostolic Age (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
    - The Bible: Six Lectures (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Canon of the New Testament (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
    - The Century of the Renaissance (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
    - The Continental Reformation (Box 4, Folder 12-14)
    - Church History: Constantine and Charlemagne; Charles the Great; Bernard (Box 4, Folder 15-17)
    - The Founding of the Malibu Community Presbyterian Church (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
    - Graeco-Roman World (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
    - The Hebrew Prophets (Box 5, Folder 22-24)
    - The History of France (Box 5, Folder 25-29)
    - The History of France (cont'd) (Box 6, Folder 30-35)
    - Lecture on I and II Corinthians (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - The Medieval Church (Box 6, Folder 37-38)
    - The Medieval Church (cont'd) (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - The Middle Age (Box 7, Folder 40-45)
    - The Palestinian Background (Box 7, Folder 46-47)
    - Protestantism in Great Britain (Box 8, Folder 48-51)
    - Understanding the Bible (Box 8, Folder 52-57)
    - The Way He Took (Box 9, Folder 58-59)
    - Women in the Bible (Box 9, Folder 60-62)
    - "Ponderings" - published book of essays by McQuary (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Marengo, Orestes
    arengo (1906-1998) was a Salesian missionary to North-East India who served as Bishop of Tura, Dibrugarh, and Tezpar.
    - Letters and brochures document Catholic missionary work in Assam, India, 1957-1965 (Box 303, Folder 13)
  - Marsh, Jonathan
    1714 - Born; 1735 - Graduated from Yale College; 1739-1794 - Ordained, served church in New Hartford, CT; 1794 - Died.
    - Outlines for sermons preached in Hartford and Harwinton (48 pp.), 1778 - 1790 (Box 214)
  - Marsh Family
    William Dwight Marsh taught at Jaffna College, Ceylon 1888-1890; John S. Marsh and Dorothy L. Marsh were ABCFM missionaries in Rhodesia/Zimbabwe 1926-1956.
    - Compiled excerpts from letters of William Dwight Marsh to his family, assembled by his grandson Dwight Lewis Marsh in 2008, 1888-1890 (Box 384, Folder 7)
    - Autobiography by John S. Marsh, with chronology; missing chapter 1; narrative for slide show re. mission work in Rhodesia/Zimbabwe, n.d. (Box 384, Folder 8)
  - Marvin, Mary
    Marvin was based in Lancaster, MA.
    - Two bound volumes entitled "A History of Missionary Work in Micronesia 1852-1910", compiled by Marvin, consist primarily of clippings from the periodicals "Light and Life" and "Missionary Herald.", ca. 1873-1910 (Box 456, Folder 14)
  - Maschio, Aurelio
    Maschio (1909-1996) served as a Salesian Don Bosco Mission in Matunga, India from 1924 to the 1970s.
    - Maschio's work in Matunga, Bombay is documented in three letters and two photographs, 1965-1966 (Box 303, Folder 14)
  - Mattoon, Stephen
    Mattoon was born May 5, 1816 in Champion, New York. In 1842, he graduated from Union College and from Princeton Theological Seminary in 1846. He was ordained as an evangelist on February 11, 1846 by the Presbytery of Troy. Dr. Mattoon was a missionary in Siam, Bangkok (Thailand) for 20 years. As a missionary he was as an interpreter to the King of Siam and organized the first Presbyterian Church of Siam. While in Cambodia, he started The Boys' School in Bangkok and translated the New Testament into Siamese. From 1870 to 1886, Dr. Stephen Mattoon served as first President of Johnson C. Smith University in North Carolina.
    - Typescript biographical essay re. Mattoon's life and work in Thailand by Mary Lourie Mattoon. See also Eddy Family (RG 30) for letters of Mattoon's wife Mary, written from Bangkok, 1928 (Box 335, Folder 5)
  - Maurer, Oscar
    1878 - Born; 1903 - B.A. Beloit College; 1906 - B.D., M.A. Yale; 1909-1942 - Minister at Center Church, New Haven, CT; 1912 - D.D. Beloit;1920-1921 - Alumni Lecturer, YDS; 1950 - Died.
    - Manuscript sermons and addresses by Maurer arranged alphabetically by title. Two folders of miscellaneous printed material are filed at the end of the collection. One folder contains typescript remarks from three funeral services (1921,1922). (Box 126–131)
  - Meigs, Benjamin
    Meigs (1789-1862) served as a missionary to Ceylon [Sri Lanka] under the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions.
    - Handwritten letter from Meigs to Samuel Worcester, written from Bethlehem, Connecticut discusses Meigs' intention to go out as a missionary, 1814 Aug 19 (Box 303, Folder 15)
  - Merrill, Gyles
    (1779-1808?) Clergyman in Plaistow, New Hampshire.
    - Ms. sermon, n.d. (Box 334, Folder 3)
  - Miller, Jonathan
    1761 Nov 26 - Born in Torringford, CT; 1781 - B.A. Yale; 1782-1821 - Minister at Congregational Church in town later know at Burlington, CT; 1798-1799 - Effective in powerful revivals in his vicinity; 1821 - Forced to leave his position because of ill health; 1831 - Died in Burlington.
    - Thirty booklets of ms. sermons and sermons notes, 1795, 1811-1820, n.d. (Box 171)
  - Miller, William McElwee
    1892 Dec 12 Born in Middlesboro, KY; 1912 B.A. Washington and Lee University; 1916-1917 Travelling secretary, Student YMCA; 1918 B.D. Princeton Theological Seminary; 1919-1962 Missionary of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. to Iran. Additional material documenting the work of Miller can be found in the Kenneth Scott Latourette Papers, RG 3 Box 89.
    - Transcript of interview with Miller conducted by Cameron Afzal, YDS student, as project for course entitled The History of the Expansion of Christianity, 1985 (Box 291, Folder 3)
    - Pamphlet by Miller entitled "Beliefs and Practices of Christians," published in Pakistan; five mimeographed circular letters from Miller in Persia, 1928-1930, n.d. (Box 291, Folder 3)
  - Miner, Nathaniel
    Miner was born in Stonington, Connecticut and educated at Bangor Theological Seminary. He was ordained in Chesterfield, Montville and served the Congregational church in Millington, Connecticut from 1830 to 1858.
    - Bound handwritten diary with autobiographical sketch, daily entries, copies of letters, 1830 (Box 284, Folder 1)
    - Bound handwritten diary, 1831 (Box 284, Folder 2)
    - "A Variety Book" - bound compilation of clippings, handwritten notes, quotations, letters, genealogical information, lists of marriages, presents, members of the church in Salem, Connecticut, 1860s-1870s (Box 284, Folder 3)
  - Minus, Paul
    Minus earned his undergraduate, theological, and doctoral degree at Yale. He was active in the ecumenical student movement and served as University Chaplain at Florida State University prior to teaching church history at Methodist Theological School in Ohio from 1964 to 1988. He was founding president of the Council for Ethics in Economics and serves on the Board of the Yale Center for Faith and Culture.
    - Documentation related to formation of the Council of the Yale Christian Community, an umbrella organization for Protestant religious groups on campus, 1954-1960 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Documentation of the Ecumenical Student Conference on the Christian World Mission, Athens, Ohio, December 27,1955 - January 1, 1956, of which Minus was conference co-chairman, 1955-1956 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Re. Student Volunteer Movement for Christian Missions, of which Minus was Student Chairman, including follow-up and aftermath of Athens conference, 1956-1960 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Articles by Minus: "The S.V.M. After Athens", "Revolution and Reconciliation"; statements on relation of SVM to Methodist Student Movement, 1955-1956 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Documentation related to proposed formation of an "Ecumenical Order" including Volume I, No. 1 of "The Journal of the Ecumenical Order for Mission", 1960-1961 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      Proposed by Minus and YDS students in1960 following up on themes of the 1956 Athens SVM conference, this "order" was intended as "an interracial, interdenominational fellowship" for service to the world.
    - Letters from Minus describing proposed "Ecumenical Order" and responses from mission leaders and others, including Lesslie Newbigin, Paul Verghese, Lee Cooper, 1960 June- August (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence re. proposed Ecumenical Order, 1960 September -December (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence re. proposed Ecumenical Order, 1961 January - June (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Research materials gathered for writing of To Stop the Weeping: the prophetic lives of Davie and Joy Napier by Paul M. Minus and Anne Napier Caffery (2010), 1921-2009 (Box 30, Folder 1-8)
  - Mitchell, Alfred
    Alfred Mitchell (1790-1831), a Yale graduate (1809?), was a Congregational minister, primarily in Norwich, CT. He was a son of Stephen Mix Mitchell, the Chief Justice of Connecticut and a United States Senator.
    - Eight manuscript sermons. Dates and locations preached are noted on front covers, 1821-1831 (Box 270)
  - Morgan, Robert A.
    Robert A. Morgan was a 1950 graduate of Macalester College and a 1954 graduate of the Yale Divinity School. He was a Presbyterian minister in Minnesota for 35 years. He received an honorary doctorate from Macalester in 1978. The correspondence, sermons, and worship service bulletins available in this collection provide an extraordinarily complete record of the life of Westminster Presbyterian Church in Austin, MN and the work of Rev. Morgan.
    - Correspondence: Tributes and thank-you letters written to Morgan from parishioners and others, 1954-1967, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 1-7)
    - Correspondence: Letters regarding a television series, 1961 (Box 400, Folder 8)
    - Sermons, worship bulletins, 1954 -1968 (Box 337–340)
    - Sermons, worship bulletins, 1969-1974 (Box 341–344)
    - Sermons, worship bulletins, 1975-1983 (Box 345–351)
    - Sermons, worship bulletins, 1983-1992 (Box 352–358)
    - Sermons, including: "Marks of Maturity"; "The Uses of Despair"; "Our Faith and Life's Tough Situations", 1967-1972 (Box 400, Folder 9)
    - Sermons, including: "Younger than Springtime Art We"; "Count Your Blessings"; "A Comforting Ministry", 1974-1979 (Box 400, Folder 10)
    - Sermons, including: "To Hell with Hell"; "We Have to be Reminded"; "Halfway through the Ministry", 1980-1983 (Box 400, Folder 11)
    - Sermons: "Varieties of Gifts"; "The Thread of Spirituality"; "Each One's Continuing Journey", 1990 (Box 400, Folder 14)
    - Sermon series: "The Character of this Coming", 1972 Dec (Box 363, Folder 2)
    - Sermon series: Lent, 1973 Mar-Apr (Box 363, Folder 3)
    - Sermon series: Lent, 1976 Mar-Apr (Box 363, Folder 4)
    - Sermon series: Advent, 1978 Nov-Dec (Box 363, Folder 5)
    - Sermon series: "Favorite Verses", 1982 Jun-Aug (Box 363, Folder 6)
    - Sermon series: Meditations on books, 1983 (Box 363, Folder 7)
    - Sermon series: Advent, 1984 Dec (Box 363, Folder 8)
    - Sermon series: Lent - "Hungers and Hopes", 1985 Feb-Apr (Box 363, Folder 9)
    - Sermon series: Advent - "Gifts", 1985 Dec (Box 363, Folder 10)
    - Sermon series: Christmas, 1986 (Box 400, Folder 12)
    - Sermon series: Advent, 1986 Dec (Box 364, Folder 1)
    - Sermon series: Lent - "Old Testament Characters", 1987 Mar-Apr (Box 364, Folder 2)
    - Sermon series: Advent, 1987 Nov-Dec (Box 364, Folder 3)
    - Sermon series: Lent, 1988 (Box 400, Folder 13)
    - Sermon series: "Why is the Church?", 1988 Apr-May (Box 364, Folder 4)
    - Sermon series: "A Summer Lectionary", 1988 Jul-Aug (Box 364, Folder 5)
    - Sermon series: "The Gospel of Luke", 1989 Jul-Aug (Box 364, Folder 6)
    - Sermon series: "Paul's Letter to the Galatians", 1989 Jun-Jul (Box 364, Folder 7)
    - Sermon series: "Christian Spirituality", 1990 Aug (Box 364, Folder 8)
    - Sermons series: "Words to Die and Live By", 1991 (Box 400, Folder 15)
    - Sermons series: "The Character of a Christian", 1991 (Box 400, Folder 16)
    - Sermons series: "The Lord's Prayer", 1992 (Box 401, Folder 17-18)
    - Sermon series (untitled), 1965, 1967, 1981, 1988 (Box 363, Folder 1)
    - Sermon series: (untitled), 1982-1988 (Box 363, Folder 11)
    - List of sermon titles, n.d. (Box 360, Folder 3)
    - Sermon notes, parts of services (Box 401, Folder 20-22)
    - Sermon resources: quotations, articles, poems (Box 402, Folder 32)
    - Notebooks containing notes on various religions (Box 401, Folder 23-24)
    - Notes from class taught at Austin Community College (Box 401, Folder 25)
    - Rotary Prayer Book: correspondence, drafts, completed copy, 1993-1996 (Box 402, Folder 28-31)
    - Prayers, 1961-1992 (Box 359–360)
    - Stories: "Stories Around the Baby"; Advent Recollections, 1985, 1991 (Box 401, Folder 19)
    - Collected writings of Arnold H. Lowe, prior minister at Westminster Presbyterian Church, 1957-1966 (Box 401, Folder 26)
    - Collecting writings of others, including Morrow, Tillich, Troeltsch, Rahner (Box 402, Folder 27)
    - Westminster Presbyterian Church newsletters, 1968 Dec -1981 Dec (Box 360, Folder 4-7)
    - Westminster Presbyterian Church newsletters; Administrative reports (1 of 2 boxes), 1982-1992 (Box 361)
    - Westminster Presbyterian Church newsletters; Administrative reports (2 of 2 boxes), 1961-1992 (Box 362)
    - Westminster Presbyterian Church directories (Box 402, Folder 37)
    - Newsclippings, photos, correspondence (Box 364, Folder 9)
    - Newsclippings, articles, booklets (Box 402, Folder 34-36)
    - Audio-visual materials: VHS cassettes: "Searching for God"; "Rites and Rituals"; "The Wisdom of Faith"; Audio tapes, including Christmas Eve music, sermon by Dr. Lowe, 1959-1996, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 38-39)
    - Artifacts: Portable Communion sets (Box 404, Folder 40)
  - Morris, Thomas
    1792 Jan 18 - Born in England; 1816 Dec 15 - Ordained deacon of Cathedral Church of Norwich; 1818 Dec 20 - Ordained priest of Gloucester - Served as Perpetual Curate of Redcliff, Bedminster and Abbot's Leigh; 1820 Feb 10 - Departed for India as missionary under the Church Missionary Society. While in India, Morris learned the "Hindustani" language and was involved in the religious and educational work of the CMS Calcutta Mission. He served as chaplain to the Bishop of Benares;1829 Jan 17 - Left Calcutta with wife and children, due to ill health; 1829 May 11 - Arrived in England. Served churches in Twyford, Ruscombe and Hurst.
    - Journal volume 1: - A diary/memoranda book containing sketchy account of daily activities in England as well as quotations and notes, 1810-1819 (Box 301)
    - Journal volume 2: diary/journal provides brief descriptions of daily activities in Calcutta and Benares, reports on travels to other towns and villages, commentary on the state of India, 1820 Oct 23 - 1824 Jul 11 (Box 301)
    - Journal volume 3: - Continuation of diary/journal, 1824 Jul 12 - 1844 Apr 21 (Box 301)
    - Journal volume 4: - Book containing thirteen letters or narrative sketches written by Morris during the period 1820 to 1824. The letters are addressed to "Rev. and dear Sir" or "Dear friend." Letters from Madeira, Cape Town, Ceylon, and Madras were written on Morris' voyage to Calcutta (1820 Mar-Jul). Eight letters/sketches describe Morris' work and travels in India. These writings provide valuable accounts of social customs, weather and the natural surroundings in India, as well as the perils of sea travel and the activities of early missionaries, 1820-1824 (Box 301)
    - Volume 5: - This volume received with the Morris papers dates from 1837 and describes travel in England and Scotland. It is written in a different hand than Volumes 1-4. (Box 301)
    - Five photographs, including three of Morris and two of his wife, Frances Hammett Morris. Some are photographs of paintings. (Box 301)
  - Morse, Henry Harvey
    1860 Oct 11 -Born in New Haven; 1885 -B.A., Amherst; 1888 -B.D., Yale; 1888-1890 -Minister - Congregational Church, Rockford, Illinois; 1890-1891 -Minister - Omaha, Nebraska; 1891-1906 -Minister - Milford, Connecticut; 1906-1911 -Minister - First Congregational Church, Danbury, CT; 1911 Mar 12 -Died.
    - Bound volume of holograph sermon notes, 1886-1889 (Box 279)
    - Bound volume of holograph sermon notes, 1889-1894 (Box 279)
    - Bound volume of Sunday School records and church bulletins for First Congregational Church, Danbury, 1907-1908 (Box 279)
    - Book of holograph notes, poems and clippings apparently utilized in conduct of funerals by Morse. (Box 279)
  - Mosley, W. E.
    Reverend W. E. Mosley was based in Hughenden, Queensland, Australia.
    - Typed letter from Mosley to the Benham family, 1964 Jun 15 (Box 303, Folder 19)
  - Moss, Reuben
    1759 Jun 11 - Born in Cheshire, CT; 1787 - Graduated from Yale College; after graduation studied theology with Benjamin Trumbull of North Haven; 1791 - Preached for six months in North Stonington, CT; 1792 - Called and ordained to serve the Congregational Church in Ware, Hampshire County, MA; during his ministry Moss experienced two periods of mental illness said to be related to a sunstroke suffered while a soldier in the Revolutionary War; 1809 - Died.
    - Fifty-two ms. sermons filed by earliest date noted on the sermon. Locations where the sermons were preached and dates were recorded by Moss on the face of the sermon, the majority of them being preached in Ware, MA. Other towns such as Pelham, Stonington, Brookfield, Hardwick, New Braintree, Branford, and Cheshire are also noted as places where Moss preached the same sermons over a period of ten or fifteen years. The last date recorded is 1807. Material donated by K. D. Frankenstein, Salisbury, CT., 1791-1804, n.d. (Box 196)
  - Murdoch, William
    - Letter written by William A. Murdoch from Mission House, Nasirabad, Rajputana, India to the Sub-Divisional Offices regarding assistance needed for Raghumath Singh, head of the Mission School in the village of Shokliya, 1915 (Box 282, Folder 12)
  - Myklebust, Jean
    Myklebust was an American Lutheran missionary at the Kingidan Kiombei Mission in Tanganyika Territory, British East Africa [Tanzania].
    - Type letter from Myklebust to "Dear Missionary Partners at Home" describes her work in Kiombei, 1958 Jan 31 (Box 303, Folder 20)
  - Neill, Stephen Charles
    1900 - Born in England, son of Rev. Charles Neill; 1939-1945 - Anglican Bishop of Tinnevelly, India; 1948 - Appointed Associate General Secretary of the World Council of Churches; Author and ecumenist; 1984 Jul 20 - Died in Oxford.
    - Memorabilia: Photograph of Bishop Neill; Cassette tape: BBC Radio Memorial Tribute to Neill (1984 Jul); Obituary: The Times (1984 Jul 24); Bishop Neill's YDS library card (Box 271)
    - Three mimeographed typescript lectures by Neill, received from Federation of Evangelical Lutheran Churches in Southern Africa, 1976: I. Nationalism and the Younger Churches; II. Tribalism and the Church; III. Evangelism an International Enterprise (Box 271)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold
    1892 Jun 21 -Born in Wright City, Missouri; 1910-1913 -Educated at Elmhurst College (Illinois) and Eden Theological Seminary (Missouri); 1914 -B.D., Yale Divinity School; 1915 -M.A., Yale; 1915-1928 -Pastor at Detroit, Evangelical Synod of North America; 1928-1960 -Taught at Union Theological Seminary; 1971 Jun 1 -Died. See additional Reinhold Niebuhr material in YDSL RG 43.